# 大家好 這些小狗養那麼久啦
Hi everyone! These puppies have been with us for quite a while already.
# 我都不知道它多重
But I never have any ideas how heavy they are.
# 秤一下它們
Let me weigh them.
# 狗
Puppies!
# 過來
Come here!
# 哇 這條最漂亮的
Wa! This is the prettiest.
# 秤一下你多重啊
Let me weigh you, alright?
# 你看 這條
Look! This puppy,
# 差不多6斤半啦
is almost 6.5 "jin" (1 "jin" = 500 grams)
# 吃那麼多幹嘛
Why are you eating that much?
# 別吃那麼多
Don't eat too much!
# 秤這條 小黃狗
Let me weigh this one, brown puppy.
# 秤一下
Weigh it.
# 哎呀 有5斤啊
Aya? It's 5 "jin".
# 去去去 你秤完啦 你就在後面去玩(註︰這個「去」是趕狗聲，我把音寫出來算了)
Chu~~! You've already been weighed. Go and play behind me.
# 5斤兩
5.2 "jin"
# 哎喲
Ayo
# 看你那麼小 你有沒有5斤2兩 怎麼那麼重
You look so tiny. Are you really 5.2 "jin"? Why are you that heavy?
# 秤對不對的
Does it weigh accurately?
# 誒 對呀
Eh? It does.
# 5斤2兩
5.2 "jin"
# 這個
This one,
# 小黑 (註︰暫不把他變成名字)
little black puppy.
# 4斤6兩 要多吃點哦
4.6 "jin". You need to eat more.
# 知不知道
Got it?
# 吃點那個 人家會欺負你的
Eat more the... You'll be bullied.
# 你們3條就秤好啦
You three have been weighed.
# 秤這條
Now this one
# 這條
This one...
# 過來 我都還沒看 你就跑
Come back! I've not yet read. Don't run away!
# 6斤
6 "jin"
# 6斤 這裡只有4條哦
6 "jin". There are only 4 here.
# 我秤一下大狗
Let me weigh the big dogs.
# 大狗不好秤哦 大狗 大狗
It's much harder to weigh the big dogs. Big dogs!
# 哎喲
Ayo!
# 那麼重哦
You're so heavy now.
# 147
A hundred and forty seven
# 誒 怎麼109啦
Eh? Why am I 109 now?
# 又胖了一斤
I've put on a "jin" again.
# 嗯
Um...
# 109
A hundred and nine
# 38
Thirty eight
# 是不是
Right?
# 38斤 那麼重
38 "jin". He's so heavy!
# 還有呢
Where are the rest?
# 都不見了哦
They've all gone.
# 我秤一下你啊
Let me weigh you.
# 哎 可以 可以
Ay! Alright, alright.
# 秤一下這條 最重的這條
Let me weigh this dog, the heaviest dog.
# 163
A hundred and sixty three
# 等於多少
So what is it?
# 拿計算器算一下
Let me take my calculator.
# 沒文化
I'm so uneducated.
# 109
A hundred and nine
# 109減去163 (????????負數了.....???)
A hundred and nine minus a hundred and sixty three
# 才54斤啊
Just 54 "jin"?
# 那麼輕
So light.
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 追狗都追得我腰痛
It hurts my back chasing the dogs.